頂峰娛樂公司
獅門電影公司
十字小溪映畫
德瑪雷斯特
電影公司
白銀映畫公司
無聊老生    誠意製作
血戰  鋼鋸嶺
+
一個真實的故事
特別鳴謝譯者dottob
《以賽亞書》40章28節
你可曾聽過
Have you not heard?
耶和華是永恆之神
The Lord is the everlasting God.
創造地極之主
the Creator of the ends of the earth.
他既不疲乏 也不睏倦
He will not grow tired or weary.
他的智慧無人可揣度
And his understanding no one can fathom.
他賜力量予疲乏者
He gives strength to the weary
《以賽亞書》40章29節
增能力予軟弱者
And increases the power of the weak.
《以賽亞書》40章30節
正值青春亦會疲憊睏倦
Even youths grow tired and weary,
青年亦會絆倒跌跤
And young man stumble and fall
《以賽亞書》40章31節
但那些仰望上帝者
But those who hope in the Lord.
必重新得力
Will renew their strength.
他們必展翅翱翔如鷹
They will soar on wings like eagles.
他們必奔跑
They will run
而不疲倦
And not grow weary.
他們必行走
They will walk
而不跌倒
And not be faint.
戴斯蒙德
Desmond.
堅持住
Hang on.
堅持住 戴斯蒙德
Hang on, Desmond.
我們會帶你離開這兒
We're gonna get you outta here.
藍嶺 弗吉尼亞州
十六年前
戴斯蒙德
Desmond.
幹嘛
What.
等等
Wait up.
跟上
Catch up.
等等 我有事要告訴你
Wait up. I got something to tell you.
什麼 哈爾
What Hal?
到頂者贏
Race you to the top.
嗨 騙子
Hey cheater.
回頭見 遲鈍鬼
See you later slowpoke.
嗨
Hey.
搭把手
Wanna hand?
我能行
I got it.
救了你
Saved you ah.
啊 你別 死吧
Ah, you don't. Quit it.
你死吧
You quit it.
上帝保佑
God sake.
嗨 離懸崖遠點
Hey, get away from that ledge.
該死的傻仔
You damn fool kids.
想摔斷脖子嗎
You gonna break your neck.
他們是老多斯的兒子
It's them Doss's kids.
跟他們老爹一樣瘋狂
Crazy as their old man.
他們挖掘了傑克埋骨之地
They dug up the corner of Jack's remain.
把他放在人行道上
Put him in the sidewalk.
你們現已認不出來啦
You boys won't recognize it now.
告訴你 我懷疑他們會認出你
Mind you I doubt they'll recognize you.
他們幾乎認不出我 當我路過
They hardly know me when I walked by.
好像我跟你一起死了
It's like I died with you.
好像我們從未存在過
It's like we boys never existed.
好了 今天就說這些
Well that's all I got for you today.
用右手擋住他 戴斯蒙德
Block him with your right Desmond.
別打了
Stop it.
聽到了嗎
Do you hear me.
他們幹嘛打架
What are they fighting about?
他們何需有理
When did they ever needed a reason.
嗨 湯姆 你能
Hey Tom do you
何必阻止而讓我兩個都打
Why stop and save me whipping them both.
這樣我只需打那個贏的
This way I'd whip the one that wins.
湯姆
Tom.
不
No.
噢 天吶
Oh God.
湯姆
Tom.
醒醒 你能聽到嗎
Wake up. Can you hear me?
你怎麼能這樣
What the hell did you done?
他聽不到了
He can't hear me.
我們得拿些冰塊
We'll get some ice.
把那個籃子拿開
You shift that basket.
好的
I got it.
他在呼吸嗎
Is he breathing?
哈爾
Hal?
哈爾 你能聽到嗎
Hal can you hear me?
哈爾你能聽到嗎
哈爾
Hal?
拜託
Come on.
上帝救救他
God help him.
哈爾
Hal?
我們在天上的父
願人都尊你的名為聖 願你的國降臨
願你的旨意行在地上
如同行在天上
我們日用的飲食 今日賜給我們
免我們的債 如同我們免了人的債
不叫我們遇見試探 救我們脫離兇惡
因為國度 權柄 榮耀 全是你的 直到永遠
阿門
你做事不經大腦嗎
What do you think you doing?
我現在必須打你
I'm going to have to beat you now.
你知道規矩
You know the rules.
聽到沒 戴斯蒙德
You hear me Desmond?
第六誡律
汝不可殺戮
戴斯蒙德
Desmond !
湯姆 住手
Tom. Stop.
這樣教育不了他 他的暴行已經夠多了
It's not going to teach the boy. His violence enough already.
好極了 賞他一個令人窒息的吻
Ok fine, you go smothering and kiss him.
告訴他這世界是個既柔軟又溫暖之處
You tell him the world is soft and gentle place.
哈爾會好的
Hal's gonna be okay.
嗨
Hey.
我差點殺了他
I could've killed him.
是的 你差點
Yes, you could have.
謀殺是眾惡之首
Murder is the worst sin of all.
取人性命
And to take another man's life.
則是最嚴重之罪在主眼裏
That is the most egregious sin in Lord's eye.
再沒別的能令他更傷心
Nothing hurts His heart the most.
我恨他
I hate him.
媽媽
Mama.
他為什麼如此恨我們
Why does he hate us so much?
哦 他不恨我們
Oh he don't hate us.
他恨自己
He hates himself
有時
Sometimes
你爸爸 我見過真實的他
Your daddy and I met the real him.
我希望你瞭解他 就像戰前我那樣
I wish you knew him like I did before the war.
十五年後
我們唱得如何 戴斯蒙德
How do we sound Desmond?
就像天使 媽媽
Like a heavenly host angels, Mom.
你知道撒謊可是有罪的
Now you know it's a sin to tell a lie.
尤其在此地
Especially in this place.
我可從未說過她們是唱歌的天使
Well I never said they were singing angels.
外面怎麼了 戴斯蒙德
What's going on out there, Desmond?
繼續 拉出來 拉出來
Go on. Get him out. Get him out.
拖出來
Drag him out.
拖吧
Just tug.
我打電話叫救護車
I'll phone an ambulance.
不 沒時間了
No. No time.
找輛皮卡
Just a pickup
要快
Quick.
好的
Okay.
林奇堡醫院
你會好的 夥計 你會好的
You gonna be fine, man. You gonna be fine.
你有專家罩
You in good hand.
何處受傷
What do we got here?
動脈切斷
That's a severed artery.
- 拿些縫線來 - 好的 醫生
- Get some sutures. - Yes, doctor.
稍稍用力按住它
Put some pressure on it.
是你用此止血的
Did you apply this tourniquet?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
幹得不錯 你可救了這娃一命
Nice work. You might've save this boy's life.
你住我們這兒 你會好的
You staying with us. You'll be okay.
我們來吧
We can get that.
住我們這兒 你會好的
Stay with us. You should be okay.
你感覺好嗎
You feel okay?
當然 醫生
Certainly doc.
部隊體檢在那邊 這裏是獻血點
Army physical is that way. This is for giving blood.
你沒事吧
Are you all right?
哦 不 那不是我的
Oh no. That's not mine.
我很好
I'm fine.
謝謝你的問詢 女士
Thank you for asking though maam.
你要什麼
What do you need?
我的皮帶
My belt.
我把它借給出車禍的男生
I lend it to the boy who had the accident.
沒它我的褲子系不好
My pants don't hold up so good without it.
呃 我可沒有你的皮帶
Well I dont' have your belt.
不 我知道女士 它仍在男生那兒
No. I know that maam. It's out there with the boys still.
好吧
Okay.
我在此采血
I'm just here to take blood.
我給你我的
I'll give you mine.
好吧
Okay.
去那個房間 跟別人一起等
Go to that room over there. Wait with the others.
我會叫你
I'll call you.
那個 那個房間
That. That room.
你以前獻過血嗎 先生
You ever given blood before, Mr.
多斯
Doss.
但朋友們都叫我戴斯蒙德
But my friends call me Desmond.
不 女士這是我第一次
No, maam this is my first time.
北美珍稀鳥類
多蘿茜·舒特\h\h
我總夢想成為醫生 只是呢
I always dream about being a doctor but ahhh
沒念多少書
Didn't get much school.
可能有點頭暈 採完後
Might be a little dizzy when we're done.
有人接你嗎
Somebody picking you up?
沒 女士 我走回去
No, maam. I'm walking back.
你住哪兒
Where do you live?
福特哈姆 女士
Fort Ham, Maam.
那挺遠的
That's away.
五或六英里
Five or six miles.
我穿過樹林
I cut through the woods.
那就七英里
Seven that way.
必是因喜歡樹林
Must really like the woods.
是的女士 確實是
Yes maam. Sure do.
好吧
Okay.
輕壓此處
Put some pressure here.
你沒事吧
You okay?
這是要去哪兒 看起來整潔帥氣
Where are you going looking all spruce and nice?
去見昨天的某人
Met someone yesterday.
醫院護士 名叫多蘿茜·舒特 我要娶她
Nurse over at the hospital name Dorothy Schutte and I'm gonna marry her.
天吶 她知道嗎
Goodness, does she know that?
還不知道但會知道的
Well not yet but about to.
你有說過話嗎 跟女人
Do you have even spoken to a woman?
除了這個尚未成家者
Other than the one that's not family.
跟她說過
Spoke to her.
既如此 給你兄弟來個大大的擁抱
In that case, come give your brother a big hug.
哦 哈爾 讓你的油爪離我遠點兒
Oh Hal. Get your greasy paws off of me.
祝我好運 媽媽
Wish me luck mama.
祝你好運
Good luck.
下一個
Next.
隨便坐
Grab a seat.
你以前獻過血嗎
You ever been given blood before?
是的 女士 我獻過
Yes maam I have.
你 皮帶男
You the belt man.
戴斯蒙德 就是我
Desmond that's me.
好吧 戴斯蒙德 我們不能連續兩天采你的血
Well Desmond we can't take your blood two days in a row.
那就好 可否拿回我的
That's good. Can we get mine back?
你的什麼
You what?
我的血 我想要回它
My blood I need it back.
那不行 不能把它還你
It dont work like that. We can't just give it back to you.
好吧 你必需還
Well you got to.
自從你用針紮了我 我就心跳加速
Ever since you stuck me with that needle my heart is beating up fast.
每次想到你則會跳得更快
Everytime I think about you beat faster still.
我以前從未聽過這話
I never heard that one before.
好老土
It's pretty corny.
是土
It is.
對啊
Yeah.
這是個恥辱 我練了一整夜
That's a shame. I've been practicing that all night.
不好嗎
No good?
我沒那樣說
I didn't say that.
有何差異 動脈跟靜脈
What's the difference between an artery and a vein?
你說什麼
What are you talking about?
男孩的車禍
The boy's accident.
動脈噴血
Arteries spurt blood.
靜脈呢
And veins?
流血
Bleed.
我覺得你在你出門前
I think you need to
該多練習男生跟女生的約會對白
practice your boys and girls dating talk at home before you come out.
我可能練過
I probably do.
我給你本書 若你那樣有興趣
I give you a book if you that interested.
約會時
On dating?
流血時
On blood.
我們後勤兵讓戰士們沒有後顧之憂
美利堅合眾國政府奉獻
戰爭序曲
還有個醫學問題 可能
Another medical question perhaps?
沒 我只覺得你是我見過的最美的女生
No, I just think you're the prettiest thing I ever seen.
那是因為我四周黑漆漆的
That's cause I'm sitting in the dark.
不
No.
你確實美麗
And you're beautiful.
讓路
Out of the way!
你得看好路再走
You need to watch where you going.
對不起 我沒想到你會介意
I'm sorry I didn't think you mind.
你沒問過
You didn't ask.
我想你可能會喜歡
I thought you might've like it.
我可能會 如果你問了
Well I might've if you asked.
你來嗎
You coming?
死開
Shit!
你為何對我們隻字不提
Why didn't you say anything to us?
因為你會試著讓我說出來 亦知我做得對
Cause you would've try and talk me out of it and know what I'm doing is right.
那主的誡命呢
And what about His commandment?
在戰爭中那不是殺戮
It's not killing in a war.
我是保護許多從我們教會入伍的男孩
I woud protected lots of boys from our church going.
戰事已起 他們要人
There's a war and they need men.
在造紙廠上班救不了國
Working in a paper mill aren't going to save this country.
看起來就像影星
Looks like a movie star.
孩子
Huh boy?
制服好看
Nice uniform.
帽子不錯
Good hat.
你提醒了我 當我們奔赴法國時
Reminds me how Hardy get in his look in this uniform
哈代穿這身制服時的樣子
when we went to France.
還記得他嗎 多蘿茜
Remember him Dorothy?
不要 湯姆
Don't Tom.
什麼
What?
我只是說哈爾穿起制服看著如何時髦
I'm just saying how snappy Hal looks in his uniform.
而所有的女孩似乎都這麼認為
All you girls certainly seems to think so.
他使她們涌向他 他得意之極
He had them flocking to him. He was most proud.
我只希望哈爾中槍時 是穿過夾克前面
I just hope that when Hal get shot it's through the front of his jacket.
像個簡單射傷 不足為慮
Like a simple entry wound not what you miss.
若是擊中背部
Or'd got hit in the back.
把他的大部分內臟跟腸子從前面炸出落得到處都是
It blew most of his guts and intestines out his front off for everywhere.
徹底毀掉他的制服
Wrecked his uniform entirely.
幸虧他死了
It was lucky he was dead
所以他從不知道他的制服看上去有多糟
so he never knew how awful his uniform looked.
離開我的視線
Get out of my sight.
你藏了什麼 高山護衛
What are you park mountain guard
你不幫我嗎 戴斯蒙德·多斯
Are you gonna help me Desmond Doss?
或者你只想讓我困住
Or you just gonna leave me stranded?
我會幫你的
I'll help you.
但你得付出代價
But it's gonna cost you.
什麼
What?
親一個
A kiss.
這純粹是敲詐
That is pure blackmail.
是的 女士 但那仍是我的條件
Well yes maam it is but that is still my condition.
事實上
As indeed
我想抱著你親
I gonna hold you to it.
等等
Hold on now.
你不會打我 是嗎
You ain't gonna slap me are you?
因我可能會帶著你跟我掉下去
Cause I'll fall off I'm gonna take you with me.
吻我即知
Kiss me and find out.
坎寧安
實用解剖手冊
什麼
What?
我得參軍
I have to enlist.
我不能留在這兒而讓他們都為我而戰
I can't stay here while all them go fight for me.
是的 你能
Yes, you can.
- 你能留在這兒 - 多蘿茜 我必須
- You can stay here. - Dorothy I have to.
我要當軍醫
I will be a medic.
我指我是去救人而非殺人
I figure I'll be saving people not killing.
我得上班了 不想遲到
I have to go to work and don't want to be late.
多蘿茜 別這樣
Dorothy. Don't.
多蘿茜 多蘿茜
Dorothy. Dorothy.
那麼你想求我嫁給你還是別的
So are you gonna ask me to marry you or what?
我不知道你會否還討厭我
I don't know you still gonna hate me?
我也不知道 你可沒問
I wouldn't know you haven't ask.
那我來問你
Well I'm asking you
全心全意地 你願意嫁給我嗎
With all my heart. Will you marry me?
那當然
Then yes.
是的 我願意
Yes I will.
何時
When?
待到你首次出征時
Soon as you get your first leave.
但我此刻仍不喜歡你
But I still don't like you at this moment.
對啊
Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
我愛你
I love you.
噓
Shhhh.
媽媽說在這兒能見到你
Mama say come see you here.
這三位是我最好的朋友
These three were my bestfriends.
愛德華·米勒
維吉尼亞州
我們一起長大
I grew up with them.
一起惹麻煩 一起追女生
Got into trouble with them. Chase girls with them.
生於一九〇〇年 林奇堡
卒於一九一八年 法國貝洛林苑
為國捐軀
我們一起參軍
I enlisted with them.
然後吾友們長眠於此
Then my friends are there.
泥草覆身 蟲蛆啃噬
Covered in dirt and grass eaten by worms.
我不想探望我崽於此
I don't want to have to visit my sons here.
爸爸我已簽約
Daddy I signed up already.
我別無選擇除了入伍
I couldn't do otherwise pop.
人人都這樣
Everybody else is doing it.
你並非人人
You ain't everybody else.
人人忙做事
Everybody else jumps in does thing quick
不加思索有如我們這種該死的蠢貨
without thinking like damn idiot fools we were.
你可知道活著的士兵所以活著
You know that soldiers who live they live
只因他們能思考 你不能
cause they can do that. You can't!
你得坐下思考 凡事禱告
You got to sit and think and pray about everything.
看看你 你現在就想想
Look at you. You're doing it right now.
你無法靠自己活著 如果你去
You won't be able to live with yourself if you go.
不 我無法靠自己活著 假如我不去
No, I won't be able to live with myself if I don't.
我要當個軍醫
I'm going to be a medic.
那將是我服役的方式
That's going to be my way to serve.
那你就去把它想清楚
There you go thinking it all out.
你以為這場戰爭會讓你稱心如意
What you figure this war is going to fit in with you?
如你所願
Your ideas?
我只曉得我不懷疑這會很難
What I know I don't doubt it's going to be hard.
不是難 是不可能
It won't be hard. It will be impossible.
無論如何
You know whatever.
如今你那瘋狂腦子裏的信仰
beliefs you had in your crazy head now.
它們永不發生 不起作用
They don't ever play out it don't work that way.
如有某些我所不知的奇遇
And if by certain I don't know miracle chance
你活下來
you survive
你不會把感謝給上帝
you won't be giving no thanks to God.
休息下 休息下 我們都需要一些空氣
Break. Break. We all need some air.
來吧 夥計們 邁邁腿
C'mon fellas shake a leg.
我理解你得跟老媽說再見
I'd understand you got to say goodbye to mama.
來吧
C'mon.
女士們 拜託 遠離公共汽車
Ladies please! Step away from the bus.
我差點忘了
I almost forgot.
我非得找根撬棍嗎
Do I need a crowbar?
拿著
Here.
我要你帶上這個
I want you to have this.
它是我的
It's mine.
你把它放在這兒
You keep it right here.
我就在那兒
Where I'll be.
我愛你
I love you.
聖經
平安回到我身邊
戴斯蒙德· 道斯
我愛你
傑克遜兵營
每次我回舖位時 我非得盯著你的蛋蛋嗎
Do I have to gaze at your deformity everytime I walk to my bed.
眼紅吧 我的朋友
Gaze upon it in envy my friend.
你還好嗎
You okay there?
你好像迷了路
You look lost.
要不你就坐這兒
Or you can sit right here.
不錯的選擇
Nice choice.
那兒能從高山看到大湖
It got views to the mountain down to lake.
蘭德爾·富勒
Randall Fuller.
戴斯蒙德·多斯
Desmond Doss.
叫他教授
Call him 'Teach'.
你聽不懂他說的每個字
You won't understand a word he says.
因為這兒沒人懂
That because no one else here can read.
那對睪丸的主人自稱好萊塢
But testicles there belong to a man calling himself 'Hollywood'.
它們看起來更像是屬於小傢伙
They look like they belong to a smaller guy.
你懂睪丸
You know testicles.
哦 嗨
Oh hey.
我剛買這雙鞋
I just got this shoes.
嗨呀
Hey ya.
格雷斯·諾蘭 來自雷德伍德 你呢
Grease Nolan out of Redwood. Where you from?
- 維吉尼亞 - 威爾·比利
- Virginia. - Will Billy huh?
你娶了你第一個表妹
You marry your first cousin?
哈哈開個玩笑
Haha just joking.
哇
Woah!
那邊的史密提跟科恩斯基臭味相投
That Smitty over there with Kirzinski's ass.
好像你更牛 雜燴腦
Like you were doing any better  chowder head.
嗨 我可不想使你丟臉
Hey, I didn't want to embarassed you.
沃爾·科恩斯基 很高興見到你
Wal Kirzinski. Nice to meet you.
嗨 乒乓
Hey Ping Pong.
你說你名字是什麼
What you say your name was?
戴斯蒙德·多斯
Desmond Doss.
邊上那位是德克薩斯·劉易斯
That Texas Lewis over there.
當他是某類牛仔
Thinks he some kind of cowboy.
還有維托·雷諾利
And Vito Rinnelli.
他也許個小 但他可是鬥牛犬
Now he maybe small but he is a bulldog.
- 嗨 你好嗎 - 戴斯蒙德
- Hi how you doing? - Desmond.
這位帥哥是幸運的福特
This handsome guy right here is Lucky Ford.
嗨
Hey.
那邊是沃克和平尼克 他們自詡為洗牌手
That's Walker and Pinnick over there. Pretending they're card shufflers.
安靜 格雷斯 好嗎
Pipe down Grease alright.
除非你想被錢塞住嘴
Unless you want to put money where your mouth is.
噢 嗨
Oh hey.
好書 對吧
Good Book right?
- 對的 - 我覺得是
- Right. - I think ahh
我覺得幸運也有本好書 是嗎 幸運
I think Lucky's got a good book, right Lucky?
這書好看
It's a good read.
立正
Attention!
啊 !
Ow!
列隊 行動
Line up. Move it.
一起來 行動 行動
Let's go. Move it. Move it.
你看起來很怪
You're a strange looking individual
你不介意我這樣說吧 列兵
if you don't mind me saying so Private?
姓名
Name?
安迪·沃克
Andy Walker.
你死多久了 孩子
How long have you been dead son?
長官
Sir?
我不是長官
I am not "Sir".
我是豪厄爾中士或軍士
I am Sergeant Howell or Sarge.
長官是叫沒用的人
"Sir " you say for useless people.
你的名字是食屍鬼 你知道
The name is Ghoul you see.
沃克
Walker.
中士
Sergeant.
是
It is.
是的 中士
Yes, Sergeant.
你的表演有失常態 列兵
There's something off with your presentation Private.
很難說
Can't place it.
是你的頭髮
Is it your hair?
還是你褲子上的皺紋
Is it the wrinkle in your trousers?
我腳上插著刀 中士
I have a knife in my foot Sergeant.
噢 是的 當然 是這把刀
Oh yes. Of course. That's it the knife.
你叫什麼名字 士兵
What is your name soldier?
史密提·瑞克
Smitty Riker.
不 你的名字是列兵白癡
No. Your name is Private Idiot.
你可知為何
You know why?
因為我腳上插著刀
Cause I have a knife in my foot.
誰會把刀插在哪兒 列兵
Who place the knife there Private?
這是個意外 中士 我在練拉伸
It was an accident Sergeant. I was playing stretch.
據我所知你不是有意插在那兒
I'm hardened by the knowledge you did not placed it there with intention.
誰扔的刀
Who threw the knife?
是我 中士
I did Sergeant.
列兵科恩斯基
Private Kirzinski.
你是印地安部族
You're part Indian.
你屬哪個部落 孩子
What tribe do you belong, son?
不知道 我是波蘭人
Don't know I'm polish.
錯
Wrong.
我相信你一定有切諾基族或肖尼族血統
I believe you must have Cherokee or Shawnee blood in you.
- 不 長官 -你在反駁我
- No Sir. - Are you contradicting me?
你這婊崽子
You son of a bitch.
不 中士
No sergeant.
讓我見識下你的印第安戰嚎 孩子
Let me see your Indian war cry son.
我不會
I don't.
你的動物圖騰是什麼
What is your animal spirit?
- 你是烏梢蛇 - 不 中士
- Are you a Garter snake? - No Sergeant.
- 你是花栗鼠 - 不 中士
- Are you a chipmunk? - No, sergeant.
你是跳舞的馴鹿
Are you a dancing reindeer?
不 中士
No sergeant.
你在反駁我 中士
Are you contradicting me Private?
不 中士
No sargeant.
好
Good.
那我從此叫你酋長
Then I shall henceforth call you Chief.
作為向你族人致以崇高敬意的標識
As a sign of great respect to your people.
謝謝你 中士
Thank you, sergeant.
你在咧嘴笑我孩子 還是你經常這樣
Are you grinning at me boy or is that your natural state?
不 中士
No Sergeant.
姓名 列兵
Name private.
戴斯蒙德·多斯
Desmond Doss.
我看庫存的玉米都有更好的體質
I have seen stocks of corn with better physiques.
讓你想扯掉哪只耳朵 列兵
Makes you wanna pull an ear off Private.
你撐得住體重嗎
Can you carry your weight?
是 中士
Yes Sergeant.
對你來說肯定輕鬆
Should be easy for you then.
下士
Corporal.
你要確保此人遠離強風
Make sure you keep this man away from strong winds.
是 中士
Yes, Sergeant.
- 列兵白癡 - 是 中士
- Private idiot. - Yes Sergeant.
把腳抬高
Raise your foot.
更高
Higher.
全部出去 馬上
Everyone outside now.
行動
Move it.
我說了行動
I said move it.
我得穿制服 中士
I'm just getting my uniform Sarge.
我有叫他穿嗎 下士
Did I asked him to Corporal?
不記得 中士
No memory of it Sarge.
我相信任何為自己自然裸露而如此驕傲的男人
I believe any man who take such pride in his natural naked state.
肯定會享受戶外的清爽
Will surely enjoy the brisk of the outdoors.
現在放開你的私處 列兵帕茲
Now move your private, Private Parts.
行動
Move it.
你這個裸露崽子
You son of an exhibitionist.
我要教你們怎麼結單套
I'm gonna teach you how to tie a bowline knot.
這樣你們能夠把你的懶屁股從高處放下
So you can get your sorry asses down from a height.
好讓我能踢它們
So I may then can kick 'em.
繞成一個圈
Create a loop.
這是兔子窩
This is the rabbit hole.
兔子出了窩
The rabbit comes out of his hole.
繞著樹子跑
Runs around the tree.
回到兔子窩
Goes back into the hole.
完成
Alright.
一起做
Let's go.
很好 德克薩斯
Very good Texas.
繼續努力 教授
Keep struggling Teach.
你從沒套過山羊嗎 好萊塢
Have you ever rope a goat, Hollywood?
沒有軍士
No Sarge.
你從沒瞪過山羊眼
Have you ever looked into a goat's eye.
沒有中士
No sarge.
好 那才不正常
Good. That would be unnatural.
你懂如不吸氣必得死
You know if you don't breath you'll die.
不錯 列兵白癡
Good Private Idiot.
恭喜你 老油條
Congratulations Greaseball,
你剛從五十英尺高處摔下來 摔斷了脖子
you just fell fifty feet and broke your neck.
棒極了
Brialliant.
列兵維托·雷諾利
Private Vito Rinnelli.
你勒死自己毫無憐憫
You strangle yourself none mercy.
你是貝內利的粉絲
Are you a fan of Benelli?
不 中士
No Sergeant.
弄高些
Get taller.
你是美國人你會更高些
You're American you'd be taller.
這是什麼 多斯
What do we got here Doss?
每個乳房各一個
One for each titty
你是結單套 孩子
You're tying a bowline boy.
不是結胸罩
Not building a bra.
有何可笑 下士
What is so funny Corporal?
說不出來 中士
Couldn't tell you Sergeant.
來吧
Come on.
來吧女士們 爬起來
Come on ladies. Pick it up.
行動 行動 給我燃起來
Move it. Move it. I wanna see some fire here.
快點
A little hustle.
給我露幾手
Show me something.
拚命跑 下 下 下
Run like you need it. Down. Down. Down.
更快 更快 更快
Faster Faster Faster
一起去清洗地道 男孩們
Let's go wash tunnel boys.
現在是時候相信你了
It is got time to trust you now!
行動 行動 行動
Move. Move. Move.
我想看到你贏
I wanna see you won it.
一起來 鑽 鑽 鑽
Let's go. Get in. Get in. Get in.
不要忘記耳後有人 一起來 行動
Don't forget behind your ears. Let's go. Move!
我敢打賭你正享受這樣 裸露狂
I bet you're enjoying this naked degenerate.
一起來 快點 快點 快點
Let's go. Hustle. Hustle. Hustle.
行動
Move.
一起來 還等什麼 一起來
Let's go. What are we waiting on. Let's go.
把屁股搬起來
Move your ass.
爬木頭 翻牆壁 別跟廢物親近
Get the wood. Get the wall. Don't kiss quitters.
加油 加油
Drive. Drive.
你沒事吧
Are you okay?
我沒事
I'm fine.
你到底什麼毛病 不准休息
What the hell is wrong with you? No one says take a rest.
把屁股搬到終點線 行動
Move your asses to the finish line. Move.
快點 快點
Hustle. Hustle.
讓你的屁股跨過該死的線
Get your asses across damn line.
啊 幹得漂亮 多斯
Aye, nice work Doss.
這是美國政府給你們每一位的個人禮物
This is a personal gift from the United States government to each and everyone of you.
標準美式步槍
Standard issue U.S. rifle.
30口徑
Caliber 30.
加蘭德步槍
M1
單配彈夾
A clippard.
肩射式半自動武器
Shoulder fired semi automatic weapon
用於把死亡同毀滅帶給敵人
designed to bring death and destruction to the enemy.
它將成為你的愛侶
This is to be your lover.
你的情人
Your mistress.
你的小妾
Your concubine.
也許是
Perhaps.
你生命中唯一的真愛
The only thing in life you ever truly love.
夥計們 一起來跳舞
Fellas let's dance.
挑個女孩
Grab a girl.
不要把槍對著前方 我今天不想中彈
Don't point your gun forward. I do not want to be shot today.
不管你多麼心癢
No matter how much you are tempted.
把槍放側邊
Place the weapon by your side.
立正
Pay attention.
有問題嗎 列兵玉米桿
Problem Private Cornstock?
尺寸不對
Is there not one in your size?
還是顏色有問題
Or is it the color that is the issue?
不 中士
No Sarge.
我被告知我不必攜帶武器
I was told I don't have to carry a weapon.
上前一步列兵 我沒聽清
Come again step forward Private. I can't be hearing this right.
我很抱歉 中士
Well I'm sorry Sergeant.
我不能碰槍
I can't touch a gun.
究竟是什麼問題
What exactly is the problem?
格拉佛上尉
沒有問題 只是誤會
No problem just a mistake.
我參軍時就說過
I told the army when I joined up.
這不可能
It's impossible.
你可知為何不可能 列兵
You know why it's not possible, Private?
不 長官
No, Sir.
因為美軍不會犯錯
Cause the United States Army does not make mistakes.
若有問題
There's a problem.
你就是那問題
You must be that problem.
我從沒想過被派到步兵連
I was never supposed to be sent to a rifle company.
他是個CO 長官
He's a CO sir.
你是個拒服兵役者
You're a "Conscientious Objector".
而你參了軍
And you joined the army.
不 長官
Well no sir.
我是個良心合作者
I'm a Conscientious Cooperator.
你在耍我 多斯
You just screwing with me Doss.
不 不 長官 我是自願的
No. No sir. I volunteered.
我穿制服沒問題
I got no problem with wearing my uniform.
向國旗行禮 盡我的義務
Saluting the flag and doing my duty.
只是不可以拿槍殺人
It's just carrying a gun and taking a human life.
你不殺人 就這些
You don't kill. That's all.
是的 長官 就這些
Yes sir. That's all.
你知道戰爭中殺戮確實很多
You know quite a bit of killing does occur in a war.
是 長官
Yes, sir.
我是說 戰爭的本質
I mean that is the essential nature of war.
是 長官
Yes sir.
好吧
Alright.
你對美軍還有任何其它要求嗎
You have any other requirements for the United States army.
還有什麼我們可以做 以確保
Is there anything else that we can do to ensure that
你會滿意地跟我們一起待在這兒
you're comfortable with your stay here with us?
他不想在週六工作 長官
He doesn't wanna work on Saturday, sir.
嗯 週六是 我是基督復臨安息日者 因此
Well Saturday is... I'm a Seventh-Day Adventist so.
週六是我的安息日 那就不允許我工作
Saturday is my sabbath so I'm not allowed to work then.
我不認為這會帶來問題 你呢 中士
I don't think that poses a problem. Do you sergeant?
我們應要求敵人別在安息日進攻
We should simply ask the enemy not to invade on a Sabbath
因為列兵多斯在此祈禱
cause Private Doss here is a prayer.
好吧 現在我們搞清楚了
Alright. Now we got that clear.
現在讓我告訴你我的要求 它們不像
Now let me tell you my requirements. They're not as
你的那麼複雜 它們極簡單
complicated as yours. They are very simple.
只要你一直待在這個連隊裏
As long as you're in this company
由我指揮
under my command
你就得服從我的命令 句號
You're gonna obey my orders Period.
你若在此做不到
If you can't do it here.
我也不信你在戰鬥能做到
I can't trust you to do it in the battle.
美軍二戰條例第八條，判斷軍人精神方面是否適合服役
我會把你視為符合第八條例
I'm putting you in for "Section 8".
我會讓你免役
So I get your discharge.
解散
Dismiss.
先生們
Gentlemen.
我想讓你們見見列兵戴斯蒙德·多斯
I want you to meet Private Desmond Doss.
顯然地
Apparently.
列兵多斯不相信暴力
Private Doss does not believe in violence.
他不願實施暴力
He does not practice violence.
他甚至不屑摸槍
He will not even deign to touch a weapon.
要知道列兵多斯
You see Private Doss
是一個拒服兵役者
is a Conscientious Objector.
所以我懇請你們
So I plead with you.
別指望他在戰場上拯救你
Do not look to him to save you on a battlefield.
因為他無疑會
Because he will undoubtedly
太忙於跟他的良心鬥爭
be too busy wrestling with his conscience
去協助
to assist.
- 中士 那不是真的 中士 - 列兵
- Sarge, that's not true, sarge. - Private
原地不動
as you were.
我意識到你們中有些人對此有著強烈感受
I realize some of you might have strong feelings about this.
那就是男人為何而戰
It is what we men fight for.
為了捍衛權利
To defend our rights.
為了保護婦女和兒童
To protect our women and children.
即使列兵多斯的信念
Even if Private Doss's belief
可能會導致婦女和兒童死亡
might cause women and children to die.
所以我希望本連隊的每個人
So I will expect every one in this company
給予列兵多斯應有的充分的尊重
to give Private Doss the full measure of respect he is due.
因為短時間內 他將與我們同在
For the short time he will be with us.
清楚了嗎
Am I clear?
是的 中士
Yes, sergeant.
你拿的是什麼 戴茜
What you got here Daisy?
你知道那是什麼嗎
You know what that is?
像是袖珍版
Just seems kind of small.
這是半大男的半大聖經
It's half-the-Bible for half-the-man.
彼得系耶穌十二使徒之首
看在彼得份上 史密提 把聖經還給他
Pete's sake, Smitty give him back his Bible.
我不記得是在跟你說
I don't remember speaking with you.
你為何不打架
So how come you don't fight?
你自以為優於我們
Do you think you better than us?
不
No.
那麼 如果你被攻擊 怎麼辦
Well, what if you're attacked.
哇
Woah.
喜歡嗎
Did you like that?
聖經說 你要轉過另一邊臉
Bible says to turn your other cheekbone.
看見沒 跟信仰無關 夥計們
You see I don't think this is a question of religion, fellas.
我認為是懦弱
I think this is cowardice.
顯而易見
Plain and simple.
你沒事吧 多斯
You alright Doss?
你娘炮 是嗎
You chicken shit  that it?
繼續
Go on.
打過來
Take a poke.
那好 我不還手
Okay I'm gonna give a free shot.
就是那兒
Right there.
打我多斯
Hit me Doss.
繼續
Go on.
什麼毛病
What a matter?
上啊
Go ahead.
不打
No?
娘炮
Chicken shit!
- 這是什麼 - 把它給我
- What is this? - Give me that.
這娘們好看
This is fine looking broad.
- 哇 -漂亮
- Wooooh. - Nice.
如今這種娘們
Now this would be the kind of broad
真正的男人才配得上
That deserve a real man.
把它還給我
Give me that back.
請
Please.
請把它歸還 史密提
Please give it back, Smitty.
請還給我 史密提
你聽得到聲音 戴斯蒙德
Do you hear voices Desmond?
不 長官
No, Sir.
我理解為上帝在跟你說話 是那樣嗎
I understand that God talks to you. Is that right?
長官 我沒瘋
Sir, I'm not a crazy person.
那你覺得大多數人怎麼看你
Then how you feel most people regard you
瘋子
Crazy person.
我不同別人我知道 只是
I'm different I know that. But
我不願弄虛作假
I'm not gonna pretend to be something I'm not.
我就是我
I am what I am.
聽起來很孤獨
Sounds lonely.
你孤獨嗎
You lonely?
那麼你聽不到聲音
So you don't hear voices.
不 長官
No, sir.
我向上帝禱告 我還
I pray to God and I
覺得他能聽見 只是那並非交談
like to think He hears me but it ain't a conversation.
就像此刻我絕不會假裝我們得談談
Like how I won't gonna pretend we have right now.
假裝 列兵
Pretending, Private?
是 長官 我知道你的打算幹嘛
Yes, sir. I know what you really wanna do is
說我是第八條例者 把我攆出部隊 只是
is give me 「a Section 8」 draw me out of the army. But
我不是
I'm not.
神明在上
Up above.
我只是信我所信
I just simply believe what I believe.
好吧 我盡量去理解
Well I'm trying to understand.
好嗎 是上帝叫你別拿槍
Alright? Was it God who told you not to pick up a rifle?
上帝說勿殺人
God says not to kill.
那是他的最重要的誡律之一
That one of His most important commandments.
大多數人把此理解為別謀殺
Most people take that to only don't commit murder.
戰爭是完全不同的情況
War is completely different set of circumstances.
耶穌說 我把一個新的命令給你們
Jesus said a new commandment I give them to you.
即你愛別人
That you love one another.
有如我愛你
Just as I love you.
我們正在跟撒旦作戰 肯定是
This is satan himself we're fighting. Sure as
虔誠的基督徒 你看得出來
good Christian you can see that.
我看得出 長官 這也是我參軍的原因
I can see that sir and that is why I joined up.
但是很抱歉 我不能帶武器
But I'm sorry I will not bear arms.
他的宗教觀確實獨一無二 但這些
His religious view is certainly unique but they
不違反第八條例的免役範疇
do not constitute ground for Section 8 discharge.
我該如何讓這樣的人聽命於我
How am I suppose to maintain discipline with a man like that in my unit?
我不知道
I don't know.
但他是一個合法的拒服兵役者
But he is a legitimate Conscientious Objector.
他必須被允許作為軍醫服役
He must be allowed to work as Combat Medic provided
他有資格在所有其它區域進行訓練
he qualifies in all other areas in his training.
也許我們可幫助緩和他的想法
Perhaps we could help make alleviant his idea.
清洗打掃整理等繁重髒的工作
好 你把他關在兵營去KP
Yeah you restrict him to barracks in K.P.
他扔上帝給你 你扔地獄砸他
He throws God at you. You throw hell right at him.
我要他消失
I want him gone.
■
禁止洗衣
浴室禁止穿鞋
多斯 你是個恥辱
Doss your area is in disgrace.
這是個豬圈
It's a pig stock.
- 有何可笑 瑞克 - 不 中士
- Something funny Riker? - No sarge.
你腦子進大糞了
You got some shit on your mind?
不 中士
No sarge.
你們沒意識到的
What you men fail to recognize
就是一隻隊伍並不會比它的最弱者更強
is a unit is no better than its weakest member.
我希望你們記住這教訓
I hope you learned that lesson.
本週末不准休息
There will be no passes this weekend.
全部去K.P
You all will be on KP.
現在全體全速徒步20英里
Right now everybody on full gear for 20-mile hike.
一起去
Let's go.
保持頭腦清醒
Get your heads right.
不要自憐
Don't start feeling sorry for yourself.
你們的自憐樣叫我噁心
Makes me sick seeing you feel sorry for yourself.
你們這些狗不知累為何物
You dogs don't know what tired is.
我們會繼續跑直到我倒下
We gonna keep going till I drop.
來吧 夥計們
Come on guys.
嗨住手 別打了
Hey knock it. Knock it off.
去睡覺
Trying to sleep here.
放開我 放開
Get off me. Get off.
為什麼你還在這裏
Why the hell you still here?
- 注意 - 原地別動
- Heed hut. - As you were.
多斯在哪兒
Where's Doss?
這對你不好 夥計
This isn't good for you buddy.
當然 我參軍不是想這樣
Sure ain't what I joined up for.
這跟你為何參軍無關
It's not about what you joined up for.
有關在此諸位的生活
About the lives of every men in here.
及你的 孩子
And yours son.
是時候退出了
It's time you quit this.
穿好衣服 我送你
Finish getting dress and I'll walk you down.
好了 多斯
It's okay Doss.
別為此羞愧
There's no shame in this.
我們走吧
Let's go.
我有額外的執勤
I got an extra guard duty.
今天 上午我得去KP 所以
Today and I'm on KP this morning. So
我不能
I can't.
好吧 多斯
Alright Doss.
列兵多斯
Private Doss.
你能認出打你的人嗎
Can you identify the men that beat you?
不 中士
No sarge.
你是說你不知道是誰打了你
Are you saying that you don't know who attack you?
我從未說過我被打了 中士
I never said I was attacked sarge.
你究竟在說什麼 多斯
What the hell are you saying Doss?
你傷得難以入睡
You bruised half your body sleeping.
我睡得很沉
I sleep pretty hard.
本周計劃濕訓 確保你戴上帽子
Planning on getting wet this week make sure you put on a hat.
我不希望任何人回來尿在奶油裏
I don't want anyone back piss in cream.
你不是想要咖啡嗎 中士
What you don't want to offer your coffee Sarge.
給你顆槍子兒如何 史密提
How about a shot right now Smitty?
講講經驗 中士
Speaking from experience Sarge.
你得問你娘 老油條
You have to ask your mom about that Greaseball.
稍息
At ease.
列兵多斯
Private Doss.
恐怕我不能准你的假
I'm afraid I can't authorize your pass.
假期只給通過基本訓練的人
This is a furlough for men who had pass the basic training.
尊敬的長官 我過了
Respectfully sir I have.
我申請了此假 三周前
I put in for this furlough three weeks ago.
我要結婚 今天下午
I'm getting married this afternoon.
你步槍不合格
It says you're not rifle-qualified.
我不需要攜帶步槍 長官
Well I'm not required to carry a rifle, sir.
上校施特爾策 他 他
Colonel Colonel Stelzer he he...
上校施特爾策規定
Colonel Stelzer stipulation was
特許多斯作為軍醫服役
Doss must be allowed to work as a combat medic.
准予他有資格在任何其它區域完成訓練
Provided he qualifies in all other areas of his training.
而你在槍械上無資格 列兵
And you have not qualified on the rifle range, Private.
很清楚
Pretty clear.
給我演示下你會拿槍
Show me you know how to handle a rifle.
我就准假
And I'll sign your furlough.
下士坎農
Corporal Cannon.
給列兵多斯你的槍
Hand Private Doss your firearm.
我不會碰步槍 長官
I won't touch a rifle, sir.
我不是要求你 列兵
I'm not asking you Private.
這是個部隊指揮官的直接命令
That is a direct order from a company commander.
看在上帝份上 多斯
For God's sake Doss.
別再廢話 退出
You stop this nonsense and quit.
拒絕
Refuse.
我則沒有追索權 只能送你去軍事法庭
And I will have no recourse but to court-martial you.
你將在軍事監獄度過戰爭期
And you will spend the duration of the war in military prison.
我不能 長官
I can't, sir.
你願意等多久 多蘿茜
How much longer would you like to wait, Dorothy?
我想得足夠久
I think it's been long enough.
這真是太遺憾了
I'm so very sorry.
有時男人會臨陣退縮
Sometimes men just get cold feet.
有的男人會
Some men might.
但我的戴斯蒙德不會
Not my Desmond.
你可能覺得我真是婊子養的
You probably thinking I'm a really son of a bitch.
只在乎規定不關心自己人
Who cares only about regulations and not his men.
可以嗎
May I?
我跟任何人一樣信任此書
I believe in this Book as much as any men.
跟任何人一樣
Just like any men.
我會被良心困擾
I wrestled with my conscience.
但當世上你珍視的一切受到攻擊 你會怎麼做
But what do you do when everything you value in this world is under attacked.
我不知道 長官
I don't know, sir.
我沒法回答那種大問題
I ain't got answer to question that big.
但我感同我珍視的正受攻擊
But I also feel like my values are under attacked.
我不知何故
I don't know why.
我不關心你的原則 因為日本人不
I don't give a rat-ass about your principles because the Japs don't.
如果他們有人攻擊你和受傷的士兵
If one of them attacks you and some wounded soldiers.
你怎麼辦
What are you gonna do?
用你的聖經揍他
Hit him with your Bible?
我已準備好為大家犧牲
I'm prepare to give my life for my men.
你無法贏得戰爭即使你犧牲
You don't win wars by giving up your life.
看吧
Look.
我隻身到此 因我不願看到你爛在牢房
I'm only here because I don't wanna see you rotting in a prison cell.
認罪
Plead guilty.
為自己爭取法庭憐憫 也許他們會讓你回家祈禱
Put yourself at the mercy of the court. Maybe they'll let you go home and pray.
讓勇士們去贏得戰爭
Let the brave men out there go and win this war.
如果我不能說服你 也許她可以
If I can't convince you  maybe she can.
他們不准我打電話你
They wouldn't let me call you.
我知道不是你不打
I know it wasn't your making.
他們對你做了些什麼
What did they done to you?
沒關係 我很好
It's okay I'm alright.
只是打了幾下牆還有些失落
Just a couple of rounds with a wall and lost.
他們說你會入獄 戴斯蒙德
They're saying you could go to prison Desmond.
甚至更糟
Leaven worth.
一定有別的辦法
There must be some other way.
我不知道將會怎樣
I don't know what that could be.
我做了他們要求的每件事 除了這件事
I done everything they'd asked me except this one thing.
他們一直待我如罪犯 只因我不願殺敵
They've been treating me like a criminal just cause I won't kill.
你盡了力
You tried.
沒人否認
Nobody can say you didn't.
但你在獄中能救誰
But who you gonna save in prison?
可能沒人
Probably nobody.
那你為何不拿起笨槍 四處揮揮
Then why can't you just pick up the stupid gun and wave it around.
你不必用槍 只需帶槍
You don't have to use it. Just made it half-way.
我不能那樣做
I can't do that.
是的 你能 這只是驕傲
Yes, you can. It's just pride.
驕傲跟倔強
Pride and stubborness.
別把你的意志跟上帝的混同
Don't confuse your will with the Lord's.
我一直很驕傲
I've been proudful.
也許我真的很驕傲
Maybe I'm proudful.
但我不知道 我怎麼能獨自活著
But I don't know how I'm gonna live with myself
若不忠於我的信仰
if I don't stay true to what I believe.
看著我們你怎麼能跟我一起活下去
Watching us how you could live with me.
我想做個男人 如你所見
I wanna be a man and I wanna be in your eyes.
我愛上你
I fell in love with you.
因你不像其他人
Because you weren't like anyone else.
你也不會想那樣
And you didn't try to be.
任何時刻都別認為你會讓我失望
Do not think for one moment that you'll disappoint me.
我將愛你
I will love you.
無論怎樣
No matter what.
我不知道他要做什麼
I don't know what he's gonna do.
他輸定了 無論如何
He loses no matter what.
他們想讓他認罪 但這會讓他開除軍籍
They want him to plead guilty but then it'll get him dishonorable discharge.
否則他就是違抗他們 他必會入獄
Otherwise he fights them he will for sure go to prison.
無論怎樣 他們會叫他懦夫
Either way they'll call him a coward
我看不出他怎能那樣活著
and I don't see how he can live with that.
謝謝你多蘿茜
Thank you Dorothy.
如果你能跟他談談
If you get to talk to him.
告訴他我們愛他 會為他祈禱 會為你們祈禱
Tell him that we love him and that we'll pray for him and we'll pray for both of you.
我會的
I will.
拜拜
Bye- bye.
我當然失去了理智
Of course I'm out of my mind.
你以為我是誰 我瘋了
What do you think I am. I'm out of my mind.
請你離開這屋
Will you leave this room.
不要 湯姆 把它放下
Don't Tom. Put it down.
放開我 婆娘
Get away from me woman.
有何貴幹 先生
May I help you sir?
我想找準將穆斯格羅夫
I wish to speak to Brigadier General Musgrove.
沒有預約可不行 那樣絕無可能
Not without an appointment you can't. That would be quite impossible.
如能勞你告訴他
If you would kinda tell him
下士托馬斯多斯將感激一個簡短的面談
Corporal Thomas Doss would've appreciate a brief word.
他在開非常重要的會
He is in a very important meeting.
我跟他在法國貝洛伍德打過仗 他是我隊長
I fought with him in France at Belleau Wood. He was my Captain.
求您女士 此事至關重要
Please maam. It's most vital.
僅需一分鐘
Be over in a minute.
你將安全到家 就跟沒事一樣
You'll be home safe and sound like nothing ever happened.
這是列兵多斯的聽證會
This is a hearing in the matter of Private Doss.
指控是他違反了其指揮官的一系列直接命令
The charge is disobeying a series of direct orders from his commanding officer.
被告怎麼說
How says the defendant?
列兵多斯希望進行無罪答辯
Private Doss wishes to enter a not guilty plea.
是這樣嗎 列兵 我以為已同意過
Is that so Private? I thought this was agreed.
你想進行某種討價還價的答辯
You want to enter some sort of plea bargain.
是的 長官 但我改變了主意
Yes, sir. But I changed my mind.
就這樣
Just like that?
你希望進行軍事訴訟
You wish to proceed to a court martial.
是的 長官
Yes, sir.
那你如願了列兵
Your on your head then Private.
開始
Proceed.
法官大人
Your honor.
列兵多斯
Private Doss.
揮舞其道德觀 有如某種榮譽的徽章
Wave his morality like it's some kind of badge of honor.
他炫耀他的蔑視
He flaunts his contempt.
靠直接違反其指揮官的一系列直接命令
By directly disobeying a series of direct order from his commanding officer.
當這些最優秀的年輕人犧牲自己性命抵禦邪惡時
When the very best of our young men are sacrificing their lives against evil.
- 你沒事吧 - 是的
- You okay? - Yes.
他們還在審議
They still deliberating?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
好吧 你把這個拿進去
Okay you go take this in there.
我不能 只有軍人才能進去
I can't. It's strictly military personnel.
那你讓他們中某個帶進去
Well you get one of them to take it in.
他們不會幫忙 他們就等著埋了他
They ain't no help. They're fixing to burying him.
任何軍事法院只需問被告一個問題
There's only one question that any military court need ask of the accused.
你否認違反上校薩斯頓的直接命令
Do you deny disobeying Colonel Sangston's direct orders?
那麼 你否認嗎 列兵
Well. Do you private?
不 長官 我不否認
No, sir. I don't.
那你為何要質疑它呢
Why are you contesting it, then?
這對你為何如此重要 使你拒絕去
Why is it so important to you, given your refusal to even
觸摸武器 即使是在部隊中服役
touch a weapon to serve in a combat unit?
因為當日本偷襲珍珠港之時 我視為針對我個人
Because when the Japanese attacked Pearl Harbor, I took it personal.
我認識的每個人都憤然參軍 包括我
Everyone I knew was on fire to join up, including me.
有兩個人在我們鎮上
There were two men in my hometown
二戰服役有關的物理 心理或道德標準
被判4F不合格 他們就自殺了 因為不能服役
Declared 4-F unfit, they killed themselves cause they couldn't serve.
為何 我在軍工廠有份工作
Why, I had a job in a defense plant.
我可以續約 但那樣不對
I could've taken a deferment, but that ain't right.
讓別人去戰鬥犧牲是不對的
It isn't right that other men should fight and die
而我只是安全的呆坐屋裏 我需要服役 長官
that I would just be sitting at home safe. I need this, sir.
我有能力有激情作為軍醫服役
I got the energy and the passion to serve as a medic,
應當在其他夥伴當中 毫無危害 只是
right in the middle with the other guys. No less danger, just...
當每個人都在取命 我是去救命
while everybody else is taking life, I'm going to be saving it.
既然這世界已把自己搞得四分五裂
With the world so set on tearing itself apart,
這對我不算是太糟糕的事
it doesn't seem like such a bad thing to me
去把那些碎片重聚一塊兒
to wanna put a little bit of it back together.
抱歉先生 無人准進
Sorry sir, nobody is allowed.
不 你不知道 我兒子就是被告
No. You don't understand. My son is the defendant.
我理解 先生 但是無人准進
I understand sir but nobody is allowed
我有封信
I have information.
好吧 表達的情感值得稱讚
Well, the sentiments expressed are laudable.
指控的事實無可爭辯
The facts of the charge seem incontestable so
那邊所為何事
What the hell is going on out there?
讓他進來
Let him go.
那是一戰的制服
That's the Great War uniform.
是的 長官
It is, sir.
長官 我得請您過目此信
Sir, I need to show you this.
恕我直言 先生
With respect, sir.
您不再是軍人
You are no longer a member of the military.
你不能參加此審議 我很遺憾
You unable to attend this meeting. I'm sorry.
這麼說真是這樣的了
Is that truly the way it works?
你為國而戰
You fight for your country
你失去了無數摯愛 然後你就沒用了
You lose so much ever dear to you. And then you're done with?
僅剩制服 無權發言
Uniform's forgotten. You have no voice?
你參戰了
You were enlist?
是的 長官 在貝洛伍德
I was sir Belleau Wood.
兩次授勳 我看了 先生
Twice decorated. I see it sir.
我想你是被告的父親
I take it you're the father.
我是 長官 托馬斯·多斯
I am, sir. Thomas Doss.
那麼作為前軍人 你知道這兒有法律
Then as former military man. You know there are laws here.
長官 我清楚法律 我瞭解
Sir, I know the law. I am.
我知道我兒子受這些法律保護
I know my son is protected by those laws.
它們受憲法約束
They are framed in our constitution.
我相信它們 像他那樣
And I believe in them as he does.
那就是為何我曾為捍衛它們而戰
That's why I went and fought to protect them.
這就是我所思所為 因為如果不是為此
It's what I thought I was doing because if it wasn't for that
我就不知道我到底去那裏幹了什麼 長官
then I have no idea what the hell I was doing there, sir.
謝謝你 下士多斯
Thank you Corporal Doss.
讓我看看這信
Let me have the letter.
你得離開
You must go.
被告作為一個拒服兵役者的權利
The defendant's rights as a Conscientious Objector
受國會一項法案的保護
are protected by an Act of Congress.
他不能被迫放棄這些權利
And he cannot be compelled to waive those rights.
權利包括本案述及之違抗攜帶武器命令
That includes in this case his disobeying orders to bear arm.
簽署 准將穆斯格羅夫
Signed Brigadier General Musgrove.
戰爭服務指揮官 華盛頓特區
War Services Commander, Washington DC.
上校
Colonel.
我撤銷控訴
I withdraw the charges.
那麼本案駁回
Then this case is dismissed.
列兵多斯 你可自由的投入戰鬥的地獄烈火
Private Doss you are free to run into the hell fire of battle
無需任何武器保護自己
without a single weapon to protect yourself.
你可恢復原職責
You may resume your duties.
作為軍醫開始訓練
Begin training as a combat medic.
- 他去哪兒了 - 走了
- Where is he? - Gone.
出來就走 我請求他留下 說他同樣想留下
Straight after. I begged him to stay. I told him he want the same.
你回家後告訴他 我愛他
When you get home you tell him that I love him.
好的
Okay.
你要好好的回到我身邊
You better come home to me.
日本沖繩 一九四五年五月
山姆大叔微微笑 平靜有如孩子貌
Uncle Sam is smiling. Peaceful as a child
但是切忌讓他鬧
But never get him rowdy
別唱了 湯姆
Cut it out, Tom.
- 你現在想玩嗎 -閉嘴
- So now you wanna play? - Shut up
- 拜託安靜下 - 閉嘴 衰人
- C'mon pipe down. - Shut up man.
把襪子塞嘴裏 小男孩 等我們到那兒時再唱
Put a sock in it boy. You save the choral for when we get there.
司機駕到
Your driver is here.
讓路
Give 'em room.
- 清空 - 萬里無雲
- Clear. -Clear blue sky.
96師
96th.
他們都剩下些什麼
What's left of 'em.
這些是他們的後備軍
These are the guys who replaced them.
我覺得不錯 這兒挺好
Seems good to me. It's cool.
安全 中士
All clear Sarge.
隊長格洛弗
Captain Glover.
中尉曼維 96師
Lieutenant Manville. 96th.
我們分配由您指揮 長官
We've been assigned to you, sir.
好的
Okay.
大家給這些夥計弄點吃的
Let's get these men some chow.
是 長官
Yes, sir.
- 這是中士豪厄爾 - 很高興見到你 長官
- This is Sergeant Howell. - Good to meet you sir.
誰是多斯
Who's Doss?
在那兒
Over there.
你是多斯
You Doss?
伊夫·謝克特
Irv Schecter
你和我和桃子在此
You and me and Peach here.
是本區僅有的醫護人員 所以
About the only medics we got left in this area. So
我想我們將一起工作
I guess we're going to be working together.
你剛從前線來
You just come off the line?
情形如何
What's it like?
我問了情形如何
I said what's it like?
鋼鋸嶺嗎
Hacksaw?
我們攻下六次
We caught it about six times.
六次被他們趕出
Six times they threw us off.
最後一次沒留下任何東西可修復
Last time wasn't anything left for something to fix.
他們是畜生
They're animals.
惡臭的畜生
Stinking animals.
小日本不關心他們是死是活
Nips don't care if they live or die.
他們想死
They wanna die.
他們不斷襲擊你
They keep coming at you.
他們從不放棄
They never gonna give up.
永不
Never.
嗨 夥計
Hey buddy.
日本鬼專門襲擊傷員
The Japs deliberately target the wounded.
去掉你所有的紅十字標誌
Lose all your red cross markings.
小日本極好槍擊軍醫
Nips put a premium on shooting medics.
那白色的靶心
That white's a bull's-eye.
拿去 我給你個新頭盔
Here I got you a new helmet.
一碼配所有
One-size-fits-all.
這是我們的目標
That's our objective.
鋼鋸嶺
Hacksaw Ridge.
我們佔領它 可能就拿下衝繩
We take it. Maybe we get Okinawa.
拿下衝繩 我們就能佔領日本
We get Okinawa. We take Japan.
吸口氣
Take a breather.
我們的海軍朋友會溫柔的請他們歡迎各位
Our pals in the Navy are gonna soften them up for us.
那死樣沒人能活
Nobody can survive that shit.
噢 但他們能
Oh, but they can.
中尉
Lieutenant.
此處的這些掩體 這裏和這裏 準確嗎
This bunkers here. Here and here. Is that accurate?
是的 長官
Yes, sir.
是的 長官 也許他們會從後面看 但這就是全部
Yes, sir. Maybe they are gonna look from the back but that's all.
完全不同 那上邊
It's all different. Up there.
全體進攻
All here accounted.
戰士們
Gents.
出發
Move out!
是血
It's blood.
糟透了
No shit.
我們已不在堪薩斯了 多蘿茜
We're not in Kansas anymore Dorothy.
繼續爬
Keep climbing.
這裏 來把你的手給我
Here. Come on give me your hand.
讓路
Make way.
拉爾夫 把這個給傑索普
Ralph, get this to Jessop.
來了
Incoming!
趴下
Get down!
他們到底在哪兒
Where the hell are they?!!!
我看不到他們
I can't see them!!!
該死的在哪兒
Where the fuck?!!!
軍醫
Medic!
在這邊
Over here!
把手放在這兒
Put your hand right here.
按住腸子
Put your hand on that gut.
來吧 我們幫你找掩護
Come on. We're gonna get you under cover.
繼續前進
Keep moving forward.
看不到任何東西
Can't see anything.
是那個嗎
It's that one
我不知道打哪兒
I dunno where to shoot.
好吧 我們上
Alright let's go.
迪諾
Dino!
噢 糟糕
Oh shit!
多斯 迪諾中彈
Doss, Dino's down.
我來了
I'm coming.
讓路
Get out of the way!
你受傷了
You hurt?
我很好
I'm fine.
來吧 我幫你
Come on! I got you.
吸氣
Breath.
盡量吸氣
Just breath.
吸氣
Breath.
沒關係
It's okay.
盡量吸氣
Just breath.
我幫你
I got you.
嗨 嗨
Hey! Hey!
給他一針嗎啡 再繼續前進
Give him a shot of morphine and move on.
他撐不過一天
He's not gonna last a day.
求你 求你了多斯 別 別
Please. Please Doss. No. No.
別丟下我
Don't leave me.
別丟下我 請別丟下我
Don't leave me. Please don't leave me.
我有孩子
I got kids.
求你 別這樣
Please! Please dont!
請別丟下我
Please don't leave me!
我不會離開
I ain't going anywhere!
我要帶你回家 我會救你 拉爾夫
I'm going to get you home. I got you Ralph.
好嗎
Okay!
我會帶你回家
I'm gonna get you home.
嗎啡來了 嗎啡來了
Here's come the morphine. Here's come the morphine.
很快就會起作用 拉爾夫 我們會轉移你
Just gonna kick it real quick, Ralph. We gonna get you shifted.
擔架
Stretcher!
起來
Get up!
繼續前進
Keep moving!
中士 我受傷了
Sergeant. I'm wounded.
你沒事
There's nothing wrong with you.
倒霉
Shit!
堅持 小子
Hang on kid.
動起來
Move!
不當士兵就當死人
A soldier who doesn't is a dead one.
我們有個優先級
We got a priority.
優先級 你還沒有分類
Priority. You haven't of triage?
他會死在我們送他們下去之前
He'll be dead before we get 'em down.
你不能肯定
You don't know that.
送他下去
Get him down!
那好
Alright!
嗯
Huh
- 好吧 - 很好
- Okay. - Okay.
好吧 走吧
Okay. Go!
沒事的 夥計 我們會送你回家
It's alright buddy. We gonna get you home.
軍醫
Medic!
救命 救命
Help! Help!
我覺得若我們看不見他們
I figured if we can't see them
他們也看不見我們
and they can't see us neither.
救命
Help!
我不能動
I took it bad.
我來了 弗蘭克 你傷在哪兒
I got it Frank. Where you hit?
我認為他們只是自作聰明
I think they just did smart-ass!
來吧 來吧 用手抓住我這兒
Come on, Come on,give me your hand here.
趴下 長官
Get down sir.
在那兒
Over there!
掩體
The bunkers!
看到了 最好待在下邊 長官
I do. Better stay down sir.
發現敵人
I got 'em!
正前方
Dead ahead!
是的 我也看到了
Yeah. I see them too.
準備好所有武器消滅他們
Get ready give 'em everything you got.
我會讓武攻隊從兩側圍剿
I'll sent them a weapon's team to flank them.
抓緊點 你會完好如初
Be there tight. You gonna be right as new.
- 好吧 - 我來吧 多斯
- Alright? -I got it Doss.
好了
Got it.
嗨
Hey
你幹得如何
You doing okay?
還好
Okay.
開火
Fire!
上
Go!
狗娘養的
Son of a bitch!
幹掉他們 接著打
Get 'em. Get on it!
- 是 長官 - 馬上
- Yes sir. - Now!
煙霧彈
Smoke!
醫護兵
Corpsman.
上
Go!
上 食屍鬼 往洞裏打
Go! Ghoul! Get in the hole.
媽媽
Mother...
上
Go!
要堅強
Be strong!
掩護
Cover!
炸藥包
Satchels!
食屍鬼
Ghoul
這兒
Here!
來吧堅持住
C'mon stick it.
堅持住 食屍鬼
Stick it Ghoul.
掩護 掩護
Cover! Cover!
狗娘
Son of a...
掩護他
Cover his ass!
上
Go!
軍醫
Medic!
我在這裏 用手按住它
I'm here. Put your hand on it.
用手按住它
Put your hand on it!
上 上 上
Go! Go! Go!
食屍鬼
Ghoul.
你傷在哪兒
Where you hit?
我不知道
I don't know.
你沒傷著頭 沒事的
You not hit in the head that's okay.
你叫什麼名字
What's your name?
安迪
Andy.
安迪什麼
Andy what?
安迪·沃克
Andy Walker.
外號
Also known as?
- 食屍鬼 - 食屍鬼
- Ghoul. - Ghoul.
食屍鬼 你沒事 你沒事
Ghoul you're okay. You're okay.
很稱職漢子們
Good job men.
幹得不錯
Good work.
就此過夜 我們守住本地
Take it for the night. We hold this spot.
我們明天消滅剩下的山脊
We mop up the rest of the ridge tomorrow.
好了男孩們
Okay boys.
給自己找個舒適安全窩兒
Find yourself a nice safe hole.
角落或靠近掩體
End or near the bunker.
我們每兩小時換次崗
We'll take watch every two hours.
我們不知道那邊是些什麼
We don't know what's out there.
死忠 愚蠢
Heads down, asses lower.
不說英語的全斃了
Shoot anything that don't speak English.
包括老油條 中士
That includes Grease Sarge?
尤其是他
Particularly him.
我不關心他是否需要尿尿或大號
I don't care if he needed to take a piss or a dump.
單獨去那邊可不安全
It ain't safe to go out there alone.
你到底要去哪兒 多斯
Where the hell you going Doss?
那邊還有很多傷員 中士
Still more wounded out there Sarge.
我和他一起去
I'll go with him.
聰明點 耳朵放低些
Be smart keep your ears down.
好了 大家找個地兒
Alright let's find a spot.
亨利在首輪15分鐘就掛了
You know Henry dead in the first 15 minutes.
直接掛掉
Just straight off.
是直接掛掉
It's straight off.
彼得森
Peterson.
大力水手
Popeye.
斯坦福和墨菲
Stanford and Murphy.
和平年代子葬父
In peace sons bury their father.
戰爭時期父葬子
In war fathers bury their sons.
別說喪氣話好嗎
Wanna stop spouting that crap out?
這幫不了任何人
It don't help none.
是啊
Yeah.
是的 你說得對
Yeah, you got that right.
在此無用
Not here.
嗨
Hey.
給我那個
Give me that.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hey! - Hey!
我們找到個腹部傷員
We got an abdominal wound.
小伙子需要血漿
This lad is gonna need some plasma.
明白了 他和我們一起
You got it. He'll be with us.
我們救了你
We got you.
我們找個洞躲躲
Should we find a hole and dig in?
我覺得行
Sounds good to me.
戴上頭盔
Put your helmet on.
你要吃那些
You gonna eat them?
我不吃肉
I don't eat meat.
自取
Help yourself.
當然了 你不吃
Of course you don't.
她是個不錯的女子
That's one heck of a dame.
你知道你有她讓我們很受打擊 是嗎
You know you find that you whack us with her don't you?
是的 我知道
Yes, I do.
別告訴她這些
Don't tell her that.
她不會太喜歡我這樣的男人
She won't be much happy with a man like me anyway.
是啊 直到她瞭解你
Yeah until she got to know you.
我是個混蛋 有時
I'm an asshole sometimes.
有時
Sometimes
你是對的
You're alright.
這些日本人很卑鄙
These Japs are sneaky.
我值頭班 現在你瞇會兒
I take first watch. Now you get some shut eye.
地獄之夢
Hell of a dream?
我夢見自己被殺
I dreamed I got myself killed.
我毫無辦法
I can't do nothing.
只需步槍
Rifles just do.
它不會咬人
It won't bite.
對 那麼
Yeah, well.
看看你周圍
Look around you.
經歷了我們這些遭遇
After what we've been through.
任何理智的人都會尖叫著找尋武器
Any sane man would be screaming for a weapon.
我從未聲稱自己理智
I never claimed to be sane.
我爸是酒鬼
My daddy's a drunk.
他屢戒屢犯多年
He fought it for years
酒癮纏身 酒後失態
but it kinda got a hold of him hard and made him mean.
至少你知道何時我曾與十人中的任何一位同在
At least you know when mine could've been with any one of the ten guys
而他們沒有一個人該死
And none of them would worth a damn.
所以你媽媽養大了你
So your momma raise you?
我記得她
I knew her.
但她把我丟給孤兒院 在我五歲時
But she gave me to an orphanage when I was five.
再沒見過她
Never saw her again.
我知道如何快速行動
I know how to act quick.
但現在我識人更快 我則確實看錯了你
But now I judge people quicker and I got you very wrong.
我爸只是經常打我跟我哥
My dad used to beat me and my brother just
因為日昇又因為日落而打我們
cause the sun rose and whip us cause it sets.
我能忍受那樣
I could take that.
但當他打媽媽時
But when he would do it to our momma.
夠了 不再
That's enough. No more.
聽清楚沒
Do you hear me?
扣下那該死的扳機
Pull that damn trigger.
不要 戴斯蒙德 住手
Don't Desmond. Stop!
但你並沒殺他
But you didn't kill him.
在心裏 我殺了
In my heart I did.
這就是為何我向上帝發誓我再也不去摸槍
So that's why I made my promise to God I ain't never gonna touch a gun again.
好吧我不會給你我的 因為你是瘋子
Well I ain't giving you mine cause you're crazy.
行動 行動 讓你們的屁股離開那兒
Move! Move! Get your assess over there!
- 我們為何不 一起撤 - 撤 撤
- Why don't we... let's go. - Go! Go!
回去 撤退 撤
Go back! Fall back! Go!
他們來自地下
They're coming from underground!
長官 長官 這是貝克6隊 請求立即支援
Sir! Sir! This is Baker Six request immediate support!
目標是北三零五一五
Target is North Thirty Five One Five
你沒注意你在哪兒嗎
Don't you notice where you are?
是的 我有留意究竟在哪兒
Yes, I notice where the hell we are
但我可不想再待在這兒
but I don't expect to be here much longer.
我叫了炮兵打擊
I called an artillery strike!
撤退 行動 行動
Fall back! Move! Move!
撤退
Fall back!
還有人
Get some!
掩護我
Cover me!
撤 撤
Go! Go!
啊
Argh!
離開這兒 小子
Get out of here, kid!
過來 孩子
Come here, son!
你知道怎麼做
You know what to do!
保持壓住它
Keep pressure on it!
不 不需要血漿
No! Don't need plasma!
把它給他
Give it to him!
在那邊
Over there!
我會沒事的 去吧
I'll be okay. Go!
去吧
Go!
- 裏斯 - 什麼
- Reece! -What?!!!
- 背上他 - 收到
- Get on the back! - You got it!
好的 回頭見
Okay see you soon.
來吧 來吧
C'mon. C'mon!
我們馬上行動 來吧 來吧
We gotta move right now! C'mon! C'mon!
行動 行動
Move! Move!
我很害怕 我很害怕
I'm scared. I'm scared.
這能止痛
This gonna help the pain.
不 不要 不要 你別這樣
No! Don't! Dont'! Don't you do that!
來吧
C'mon!
來吧 史密提留下陪我
C'mon Smitty you stay with me!
我們得一起行動
Let's go we gotta move!
嗨 幫我把他送下去
Hey! Help me get him down.
幫我把他送下去
Help me get him down!
來吧讓我們行動 來吧
Come on let's move. Come on.
幫不了你 夥計 他走了
Can't help you buddy. He's gone.
沒有 來吧 我們要離開這兒
No. Come on. We got to get out of here.
放下繩子
Down the rope!
下一個
After it.
他要我去哪兒
Where does it He want me?
我不明白
I don't understand.
我聽不到你
I can't hear You.
救我
Help me!
好吧
Alright!
有多少
How many?
只有32個下來了 長官
32 only came down, sir.
上帝啊
Good Lord.
我們四下找找
Let sow them up.
是 長官
Yes, sir.
哈利
Harry.
我是戴斯蒙德
It's Desmond.
我們會醫好你 你只需保持呼吸 好嗎
We gonna fix you up. You just gotta keep breathing. Okay
上校想見你 長官
Colonel want to see you, sir.
我需要你的吉普
I need your jeep.
你兩個留此警戒 提防日本鬼子
You two stay here and keep watch. Keep your eyes peel for Japs.
不行 但是
No. But the...
留此警戒
Stay here and keep watch!
遵命 長官
Yes, sir.
救命 救我
Help! Help me.
當心
Watch out!
我救你
I got you.
把手放上面 保持按住它
Put your hand on it. Keep pressure on it.
我會回來的
I'm coming back.
- 好嗎 - 別離開
- Okay. - Don't leave.
輕些 夥計們 輕些
Easy fellas. Easy.
就放這兒
Here we go.
好了夥計們 一起來
Okay guys let's go.
一 二 三 行動
One-Two-Three. Move.
沒關係 我們還在一起
It's okay.All we together
我把你救到這兒了
I got you here
只需坐穩 好嗎
Just sit tight, okay.
你沒事夥計
You okay buddy.
混蛋 這會起作用
Son of a gun. This is gonn a work
每條腿一個
One for each leg.
我們馬上幫你穿好
We gonna get you dress up in a jiffy.
再放你下去
and get you down.
我救你
I got you.
我現在救你
I got you now.
你得相信我
You can trust me.
日本佬
Japs!
等等 我們的人 等等
Hold on. One of ours. Hold on.
一起去 一起去
Let's go. Let's go.
我救你 我救你
I got you. I got you.
來吧
Come on.
我救你 你沒事了
I got you. You okay.
你沒事了
You okay.
嗨
Hey!
又一個
Another one.
上校 呼叫取消炮擊鋼鋸嶺 不能投彈
Colonel. Call off the artillery attack on Hacksaw. Couldn't pull it in.
還有超過100人在那兒
There's still over a 100 men left out there.
告訴他們取消炮擊鋼鋸嶺
Tell them to call off the artillery on Hacksaw.
埃布爾-貝克-壹  結束
Able-Baker-One ,over.
坐下 傑克
Sit down Jack.
我給你喝的
I get you a drink.
只是失去掩護
Just lost our cover.
他們要開始了 我們趕緊行動
They're starting. We gotta move.
剛好
About time.
他們不斷下來
They just keep coming.
好的 抬起來
Okay. Pick it up.
我抬這邊
I got this.
多斯
Doss.
救命
Help.
救我
Help me.
你必須信任我
You gonna have to trust me.
吸口氣
Take a breath.
我們走夥計
Let's go buddy.
我們走
Let's go.
傑克 你不知道你在那兒的人是死是活
Jack. You don't know if your men out there are dead or alive.
沒有援軍 我們不能回到上邊去
We can't go back up there without reinforcement.
你會讓剩下的人也送命
You'll end up killing the rest.
那就給我援軍
So give me the reinforcement.
我沒有新人 我沒有任何連隊
I don't have any fresh men. I don't have any troops.
今天三個營被消滅
3 batallions got wipe out today.
新兵到這兒還要一天多
And it'll take more than a day to get men here.
我需要他們早點到
I need them faster than that.
沒關係 沒關係
It's okay. It's okay.
沒事了 沒事了
It's alright. It's alright.
沒關係
It's okay.
嗎啡 好的
Morphine it's good.
噓
Shhh.
軍醫 軍醫
Medic. Medic.
軍醫 我是多斯
Medic. It's Doss.
我是多斯 安靜
It's Doss. Be quiet.
安靜
Be quiet.
我們來救你 你傷哪兒
We got you. Where you hit?
我看不見
I can't see.
安靜 安靜點
Be quiet. Just be quiet.
現在別動
Hold still now.
我救你
I got you.
抓穩
Hold tight.
弄好了
There you go.
試著看 試著看
Try that. Try that.
我以為我瞎了
I thought I was blind.
噓
Shhh.
冷靜
Keep it down.
你能走嗎
Can you walk?
我不知道
I don't know.
- 因為我們得離開這兒 -好的
- Cause we gotta get out of here.- Okay.
好了 我們接住你了
Okay we got you.
我們接住你了
We got you.
嗨 你
Hey, there.
是我 戴斯蒙德
It's me Desmond.
醫好你
Fix you up.
你準備離開這兒 我肯定
You ready to get out here. I'm sure am.
懇請上帝
Please Lord.
讓我再救一個
Help me get one more.
請讓我再救一個
Please help me get one more.
再一個
One more.
讓我再救一個
Help me get one more.
再一個
One more.
讓我再救一個
Help me get one more.
再一個
One more.
來了
Coming through.
這些傢伙到底哪來的
Where the hell these guys coming from?
鋼鋸嶺
Hacksaw.
我以為他們已撤完了
I thought they pulled out.
並非所有
Not all of them.
某瘋子在那裏把傷員從頂上放下來
Some nuts out there drive the wounded from the top.
甚至放下了幾個日本佬
Even lowered a couple of Japs.
他們沒能挺得住
They didn't make it
回頭直接帶給你
Get back with you directly.
輕點 輕點
Easy. Easy.
滿了 出發
All set. Move out.
我們走
Let's go.
到這兒來
Get in here.
到處都是日本人
There's Nips everywhere.
狗娘養的
Son of a bitch.
列兵 玉米稈
Private Cornstock.
你一無是處如果不是滿帶驚喜
You're nothing if not full of surprises.
- 你想要些嗎啡 - 想得很
You want some morphine. - Hell yes.
那條或兩條
That or both.
好吧
Okay.
來了
There.
給你
There you go.
好吧
Alright.
放鬆 讓我看看
Easy. Let me see.
這樣如何 好吧 不壞
How's this? Okay. Not bad.
讓我看看
Let me see.
我會做得比這還要糟
I'll make much much than this.
但女孩們還是不會吻你
But girls still won't kiss you.
中士
Sarge.
你在此待一會兒可好
You okay here for a while?
好的 我還好
Yeah I'm fine.
儘管離開
Get outta here.
我會回來
I'm coming back.
你準備好了 我們走
You ready? Let's go.
你跟我 來吧
You and me. C'mon.
上尉 有事你得瞧瞧
Captain. Something you gotta see.
整個夜裏我們的人被一個個的放下來
Our guys have been coming down in droves all night.
而好萊塢在此
And Hollywood's here.
我從沒想過還能再見此人
I never thought I'd see that guy again.
來吧跟我來 他在這兒
Come on follow me. He's right here.
這到底是怎麼回事
What the hell is this?
你好 長官
How you doing sir?
嗨 帽子
Hey, Cap.
上尉
Captain.
很高興看到你 孩子
It's good to see you kid.
上帝保佑 長官
God bless, sir.
你怎麼下來的 孩子
How you get down, son?
是多斯
It's Doss.
豪厄爾仍在那兒
Howell's still out there.
豪厄爾和多斯做的
Howell and Doss did this?
不 長官 只是多斯
No, sir. It's just Doss.
- 只是多斯 - 只是多斯
- Just Doss? - Just Doss.
對 多斯 那懦夫
Yeah Doss the Coward.
你喜歡鞋上的槍 不是嗎
You like gun on a shoe ain't ya.
給我這個
Give me this.
現在打靶太遲了 你不覺得
It's a bit late for target practice now don't you think.
跳上來
Jump on it.
你開玩笑吧
You kidding?
不 我來拖你
No, I'm gonna drag you.
一起幹吧
Let's do it.
- 好了嗎 －好了
- Ready? - Yeah
我們走
Let's go!
我們有追兵
We got company.
來吧
Come on.
我們得跳
We're gonna jump.
你在耍我吧 玉米稈
You gotta be kidding me, Cornstock?
你是結單套 不是結胸罩
You got a bowline, not building a bra.
來吧
Come on!
- 好沒 - 好了
- Ready? - Ah huh.
下去
Get off!
- 放下我 - 是 中士
- Put me down! - Yes, Sergeant.
中士豪厄爾
Sergeant Howell.
多斯還在那兒
Doss is still up there.
到底咋回事
What the hell?
他被日本佬尾追
He's got Japs on his tail.
我們接住他了
We got him.
很好 很好
It's good. It's good.
喔 好了 好了 多斯
Woah. It's okay. It's okay. Doss.
你安全了
You're safe.
好吧
Okay.
戴斯蒙德
Desmond.
放鬆
Easy.
這兒 來吧
Here come on.
坐下
Take a seat.
你受傷了
Are you wounded?
沒有
No.
大家立即送這名士兵去醫療篷
Let's get this soldier to a hospital tent right now.
來吧 現在放輕
Come on easy now.
放鬆 放鬆
Easy. Easy.
伊夫在哪兒
Where's Irv?
伊夫
Irv.
你是說謝克特軍醫
You mean Schecter the Medic?
他沒能挺住
He didn't make it.
他死於震傷
He died of shocked.
沒有血漿
No plasma.
抱歉
Sorry.
我只看到一個瘦小子
All I saw was a skinny kid.
我不知道你是誰
I didn't know who you were.
你比任何別的男人報效祖國所做的多得多
You done more than any other men could've done in a service to his country.
我此生從未如此看錯人
I have never been more wrong about someone in my life.
我希望有天你能原諒我
I hope one day you could forgive me.
我們明天必須回到上邊
We have to go back up tomorrow.
我意識到明天是你的安息日
I realize that tomorrow is your Sabbath.
這些人大多數不相信你所信仰的方式
Most of these men don't believe the same way you do.
他們如此相信
They believe so much
你有多堅信
How much you believe.
你在山脊上的所為就是奇跡
What you did on that Ridge is nothing short of miracle.
他們想要一塊
They wanna piece of it.
沒有你 他們不會去那兒
They're not gonna go up there without you.
你到底拖延什麼 上尉
What the hell is your delay, Captain?
你應該在10分鐘前開始進攻
You supposed to begin that assault 10 minutes ago.
我們在等待長官
We're waiting, sir.
等什麼
Waiting for what?
列兵多斯為我們完成祈禱 長官
Private Doss to finish praying for us, sir.
列兵多斯在為你祈禱 列兵多斯到底是誰
Private Doss is praying for you. Who the hell is Private Doss?
我們去幹活
Let's go to work.
趴下
Down!
趴下 趴在地上
Get down! Get down on the ground!
立即趴在地上
On the ground now!
躺下 躺下 我有嗎啡
Lay down! Lay down! I got the morphine.
我們走 我們走 我們帶這個人離開這兒
Let's go! Let's go. Let's get this man outta here.
走 走
Go! Go!
我的聖經
My Bible.
停下 停下 停下
Stop! Stop! Stop!
我的聖經 我的聖經
My Bible. My Bible.
好吧
Okay.
你回家了 戴斯蒙德
You going home Desmond.
我們已拿下鋼鋸嶺
We've taken the Hacksaw.
等下 等下 戴斯蒙德
Hold up! Hold up! Desmond.
戴斯蒙德
Desmond.
戴斯蒙德·多斯在鋼鋸嶺戰役中一共救下75名傷員.
他是首位拒服兵役卻獲得榮譽勳章的士兵，這也是美軍授予戰火勇士的最高榮譽.
戴斯蒙德和多蘿茜的婚姻一直延續到她於一九九一年去世.
對於自己的英雄事跡，他很謙虛，將其歸功於他的信仰.
我一直在祈禱
I was praying the whole time.
我只是開始祈禱上帝請讓我再救一個
I just start praying to the Lord please let me get one more.
戴斯蒙德·多斯 - 二〇〇三年
當我救多一個
When I got this
我說 好吧 上帝請讓我再救一個
I said "Alright Lord please help me get one more".
他說 「真正的英雄都長眠在那裏.」
我認為若要去妥協他人的信念
I would say anyone is wrong
哈羅德（哈爾）·多斯
任何人都是錯的
to try to compromise somebody's conviction.
我不在乎是軍隊或者是什麼
I don't care it's the army or what it is.
當你持有信念
When you're on a conviction
那不是笑話
That is not a joke.
那就是你
That's what you are.
傑克·格拉佛上尉
即使我對他說那些關於攜帶步槍的事
Even though I said those things to him in regard to carrying a rifle.
然而他永遠不會站在我這邊
Then he would never be on my damn side at all
除非他拿了槍
unless he had a rifle.
但是從長遠來看
But then in the long run.
發現他是一個活著的最勇敢的人
Finding out that he was one of the bravest person alive.
而讓他停止挽救我的生命
And then to have him ended up saving my life
則會是對整件事的諷刺
was the irony of the whole thing.
血順著這傢伙的臉跟眼流下
Blood it ran down through this fellow's face and eyes.
那是當他開始呼喊軍醫的時候
It was when that he go in and called for medic.
我從水壺取水 拿出繃帶
I took the water from my canteen and got some bandages.
我沖洗他的臉
And I wash his face.
當我擦拭
And when I wipe
沖洗他的雙眼 眼睛睜開了
Washed up his eyes. Eyes came out
夥計 他頓時亮了
Man, he just lit up.
他說 我以為我瞎了
He says I thought I was blind.
如我沒有任何東西多於他給我的微笑
And if I hadn't got anything more to what that smile he gave me.
我不會得到很好的回報
I wouldn't have been well repaid.
戴斯蒙德·多斯於二〇〇六年三月逝世.
享年八十七歲.
導演
梅爾·吉布森
編劇
羅伯特·施恩坎
安德魯·奈特
製片人
比爾·麥克尼柯
大衛·珀馬特
製片人
特裏·本尼迪克特
保羅·庫瑞
布魯斯·戴維
製片人
布萊恩·奧利弗
威廉姆·D·約翰森
執行製片人
戴維·古瑞特豪斯
斯圖華特·福特
泰勒·湯普森
埃裏克·格林菲爾德
執行製片人
瑞克·尼西塔
倫·布拉瓦特尼克
勞倫斯·班德
勞倫·塞利格
執行製片人
克裏斯托弗·伍德羅
邁克爾·巴希克
詹姆斯·M·弗農
巴蒂·帕特裏克
執行製片人
蘇珊妮·沃倫
萊尼·科恩伯格
馬克·K·曼紐爾
泰德·奧尼爾
預算控制製片
芭芭拉·吉布斯
聯合製片人
扎克·梅凱尼克  斯蒂夫·朗格
格雷格瑞·克魯斯比  伊萊科薩·魯斯
傑森·西格雷福斯
攝影指導
西蒙·達根
藝術指導
巴瑞·羅賓森
剪輯
約翰·吉爾伯特
音樂
魯伯特·格雷格森·威廉斯
服裝設計
利茲·加德納
化妝及髮型設計
肖恩·托馬斯
第二攝制組導演
米克·羅傑斯
視覺特效總監
克裏斯·戈德弗雷
選角導演
妮姬·巴瑞特
安德魯·加菲爾德
薩姆·沃辛頓
盧克·佈雷西
泰莉莎·帕爾墨
雨果·維文
瑞切爾·格裏菲斯
以及
文斯·沃恩
頂峰娛樂公司 和 十字小溪映畫
榮譽出品
德瑪斯特媒體 和 白銀映畫公司
攜手獻映
拓宇國際發行公司 和 愛電影製片公司
聯袂製作
瓦迪安娛樂 和 麒麟影業
傾力加盟
血戰鋼鋸嶺
混亂電影公司 / 置換演示報告
承製
梅爾·吉布森
作品
無聊老生製作   謝謝各位觀賞